# Stephan Kostov

stephank179@gmail.com ❖ (+44) 7446903000 ❖ github.com/stephankostov ❖ Edinburgh, Scotland

A diligent and forward-thinking team-player with a comprehensive set of problem-solving and analytical skills. These were developed through experience in engineering both software and mechanical, along with a core data skillset through an MSc in Data Analytics. Most recently I've had the opportunity to take a sabbatical break from work to build competence in all things AI through courses, textbooks, and AI-agent development projects. With these skills I am now wholeheartedly committed to contribute in the fascinating and exciting field of AI.

#### **EDUCATION**

### University of Glasgow

September 2020 - June, 2021

MSc Data Analytics (1st Class)

Glasgow, Scotland

- Relevant Classes: Statistics, Bayesian Statistics, Probability, Data Analysis, Deep Learning for Big Data, Machine Learning, Application Development.
- Project: Dissertation in "Predicting Astrophysical Properties of Stars" through Statistical and Machine Learning modelling.

## University of Strathclyde

September 2015 - May, 2020

BEng Mechanical Engineering (1st Class)

Glasgow, Scotland

- Core Projects:
  - o Dissertation in "Optimising Space Flight Trajectories" through an exploration and tuning of the state-of-the-art computation optimisation algorithms.
  - o Design and Manufacturing of a model drag racer car in a team of 5.
- Competing in the University Men's Basketball 1st team (division 1).

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Sky Group Ltd

April. 2021 – December 2022

DevOps / Software Engineer

Livingston, Scotland

## DevOps Infrastructure Responsibilities:

My main responsibilities as the DevOps engineer for a scrum team was to manage the deployments and infrastructure around the software development lifecycle.

- Service Deployment
  - o Orchestrated seamless deployments of team's services, ensuring continual availability and reliability.
  - o Proficiency in service containerisation using Kubernetes to host Dockerised Images.
  - o Configuring and managing legacy services on Linux.
- Monitoring and Metrics
  - o Implementing robust performance metrics pipelines to InfluxDB.
  - o Designing interactive dashboards with Grafana for real-time time-series data visualisation.
- Log Storage
  - o Implementing readable logging using ElasticSearch.
  - o Leveraging Apache Kafka message queues for robust log storage.
- CI/CD Deployment Pipelines
  - o Streamlining software deployment pipelines using Jenkins and Gitlab, ensuring reliable hands-off deployments.
  - o Automating testing, integration, and production workflows.
- Server Setup
  - o Proficiently managed both Unix and Windows servers, optimising for performance and security.

## **Chatbot Development Project:**

In addition to my DevOps responsibilities, I also completed a development project to provide a foundation for further automations for our support team.

- Developed an internal chatbot application for Slack and Microsoft Teams.
- Chatbot served as a core platform to add automations for the support team's requests.
- Built in Javascript from scratch following test-driven development and functional programming paradigms.

## Hong Kong Polytechnic University (IAESTE Internship Program)

June 2020 – August 2020

Aeronautical Engineering Intern

Hong Kong

- Assisting a research team in investigating aerofoils by computationally simulating their physical hydro-tunnel experiments for use in an academic paper.
- Presentation of internship experience to colleagues, university board members, and internship program staff.

#### ADDITIONAL COURSES AND LEARNING

FastAI: Practical Deep Learning Foundations

February 2023 - May 2023

- o Course on the foundations of deep learning, and the state-of-the-art models.
- FDM Software Development Graduate Program

November 2020 - April 2021

o Training course in full-stack OOP with Spring Boot Java and React, also including separate weeks for each SQL, Python, and Unix.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming: Python, Javascript, Bash, HTML/CSS, R, Java, Groovy, MATLAB
- Data Science: PyTorch, NumPy, Pandas, Huggingface
- Data Visualisation: Matplotlib, Pandas, R, Grafana
- Statistics: Regression, Classification, Clustering
- Web Development: React, Spring Boot
- Technologies: Unix, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Kafka, ElasticSearch, Azure
- Databases: Oracle SQL, InfluxDB, MongoDB

#### **INTERESTS**

Basketball, Rock Climbing, Videogames, Piano, Reading, Cooking, Skiing, Travel